strands.com 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy - Strands.com

## Privacy Policy

**This is the Privacy Policy of Strands Labs, Inc. and of its affiliated companies (“Strands”), which was updated on 23 May 2018.**

The Strands Privacy Policy has been updated in order to comply with General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

Strands understands the protection of personal data is a fundamental human right. The Strands Privacy Policy mainly covers the following parts:

  1. Strands identity data and address;
  2. purposes of the processing of your personal data and the legal basis for the processing;
  3. the recipients of your personal data;
  4. retention specifications of your personal data;
  5. international transfers of your personal data;
  6. privacy questions;
  7. non-compulsoriness of your answers to the questions Strands may ask;
  8. possible consequences of the providing your personal data and of failure to provide them to Strands;
  9. exercising of your rights of access, to rectification, to erasure, to restriction of processing, to data portability and to object to processing, your personal data.

### Strands identity data and address

Strands Labs, Inc. complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

### Information Collection

Following you can find the contact details of Strands as a data processor controller:

Identity: Strands Labs, Inv. – T.I.N.: ESA63449243. Address: Almogavers 119, 08018, Barcelona, Spain. Telephone: +34932241694. E-mail: [gdpr@strands.com](mailto:gdpr@strands.com)

### Purposes of the processing of your personal data and the legal basis for the processing

Strands is a developer of software for companies, which is used by banks and other financial institutions, and a related to that software services provider. Strands develops a software in order to be used by banks and other financial institutions for processing of financial personal data of its customers. Strands develops a business-to-business software under Strands’ trademark. Strands does neither process any personal data of its clients, like banks or other financial institutions, nor any personal data of the customers of its clients. You may be asked to provide your personal information anytime you are in contact with Strands only in connection to your commercial or professional activity related to Strands’ clients, prospects or providers, and with the purpose of entering into, and managing the business relationships between Strands and any of its clients, prospects or providers. Strands only process your contact data, as name(s) and surname(s), company, job positions, e-mails addresses, telephone numbers, etc. Strands and its affiliates may share your personal information with each other and use it consistent with this Privacy Policy. They may also combine it with other information to provide and improve our products, services, content, and advertising. You are not required to provide the personal information that we have requested.

### Recipients of your personal data

The recipient of your personal data is only Strands. In case your personal data are to be transferred, Strands will inform you about in advance. Personal information will only be shared by Strands to provide or improve our products, services and advertising; it will not be shared with third parties for their marketing purposes.

### Retention specifications of your personal data

Strands makes it easy for you to keep your personal information accurate, complete, and up to date. We will retain your personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

### International transfers of your personal data

All the information you provide may be transferred or accessed by entities around the world as described in this Privacy Policy. The controller of your personal data is Strands Labs, Inc. Strands usually does not transfer any personal data outside European Economic Area. If Strands does that, will use approved Model Contractual Clauses for the international transfer of personal information collected in the European Economic Area and Switzerland. Strands, as a global company, has a number of legal entities in different jurisdictions which are responsible for the personal information which they collect and which is processed by Strands Labs, Inc.

### Privacy questions

If you have any questions or concerns about Strands’ Privacy Policy or data processing or if you would like to make a complaint about a possible breach of local privacy laws, please contact Strands at [gdpr@strands.com](mailto:gdpr@strands.com). 

When a privacy question is received by Strands, Strands have a dedicated team which seeks to address the specific concern or query which you are seeking to raise. Where your issue may be more substantive in nature, more information may be sought from you. All such substantive contacts receive a response. If you are unsatisfied with the reply received, you may refer your complaint to the relevant regulator in your jurisdiction. If you ask Strands, Strands will endeavor to provide you with information about relevant complaint avenues which may be applicable to your circumstances.

### Non-compulsoriness of your answers to the questions Strands may ask

In case Strands asks you any questions related to the purposes of the processing of your personal data under this Privacy Policy, your answers to them are optional and without any compulsoriness.

### Possible consequences of the providing your personal data and of failure to provide them to Strands

The providing your personal data to Strands will allow Strands to provide and improve Strands’ products, services, content, and advertising, in benefit of the companies you are working to or you are collaborating with. You are not required to provide the personal information that we have requested. In case Strands cannot be provided with your personal data, it would difficult for Strands to adequately provide and improve Strands’ products, services, content, and advertising, in benefit of the companies you are working to or you are collaborating with.

### Exercising of your rights of access, to rectification, to erasure, to restriction of processing, to data portability and to object to processing, your personal data

You can ensure that your contact information and preferences are accurate, complete, and up to date by logging at any time, contacting Strands at [gdpr@strands.com](mailto:gdpr@strands.com). Strands provides you with access your personal data throughout providing you with a copy of them for any purpose, including the requests that Strands correct your personal data if they are inaccurate, to delete them, to restrict their processing, their portability and to object their processing, if Strands is not required to retain them by law or for legitimate business purposes. Strands may decline to process requests that are frivolous or vexatious, jeopardize the privacy of others, are extremely impractical, or for which access is not otherwise required by local law. Access, rectification, erasure, restriction of processing, portability or objection to processing can be requested contacting Strands at [gdpr@strands.com](mailto:gdpr@strands.com).

### Cookies and Other Technologies

Strands’ websites, online services, interactive applications, email messages, and advertisements may use “cookies” and other technologies, such as pixel tags and web beacons. These technologies help Strands better understand user behavior, tell us which parts of our websites people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. We treat information collected by cookies and other technologies as nonpersonal information. However, to the extent that Internet Protocol (IP) addresses or similar identifiers are considered personal information by local law, we also treat these identifiers as personal information. Similarly, to the extent that non-personal information is combined with personal information, we treat the combined information as personal information for the purposes of this Privacy Policy.

Strands and our partners also use “cookies” and other technologies to remember personal information when you use our website, online services, and applications. Strands goal in these cases is to make your experience with Strands more convenient and personal.

As is true of most internet services, Strands gather some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit websites and applications, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. Strands use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, to improve our product and services, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Strands may use this information in our marketing and advertising services.

### Service Providers

Strands shares personal information with companies who provide services such as information processing (Google Analytics, Hubspot), managing and enhancing customer data, providing customer service, assessing your interest in our products and services, and conducting customer research or satisfaction surveys. These companies are obligated to protect your information and may be located wherever Strands operates. It may be necessary − by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from public and governmental authorities within or outside your country of residence − for Strands to disclose your personal information. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that for purposes of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate. We may also disclose information about you if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions or protect our operations or users. Additionally, in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale we may transfer any and all personal information we collect to the relevant third party.

### Protection of Personal Information

Strands takes the security of your personal information very seriously. When your personal data is stored by Strands, we use computer systems with limited access housed in facilities using physical security measures. When you use some Strands products, services, or applications or post on an Strands forum, chat room, or social networking service, the personal information and content you share is visible to other users and can be read, collected, or used by them. You are responsible for the personal information you choose to share or submit in these instances.

### Our Companywide Commitment to Your Privacy

To make sure your personal information is secure, we communicate our privacy and security guidelines to Strands employees and strictly enforce privacy safeguards within the company.

Strands may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy.
